[{"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b68c", "question": "What automaker produced a model named Stag from 1970 to 1977?", "answer": "Triumph", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b56d", "question": "Who scored both the \"Hand of God\" goal and the \"Goal of the Century\" in the same game, during the 1986 World Cup?", "answer": "Diego Maradona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b60", "question": "What is the highest female voice in a choir?", "answer": "Soprano", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b02f", "question": "What country presented the US with a gift of cherry trees in 1912?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ea", "question": "What is the most general and highest taxonomy rank of organisms?", "answer": "Domain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d076ba870e6f05ba60085d", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Taming of the Shrew\", who courts the shrew?", "answer": "Petruchio", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c49", "question": "What is the name of the hero in most of Tom Clancy's novels?", "answer": "Jack Ryan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58c9f76cb4e2c7fbd3896749", "question": "What company\u2019s tea shipment was destroyed during the Boston Tea Party in 1773?", "answer": "East India Company", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ba9", "question": "Which book begins with the words \"It was a bright cold day in April, and the clocks were striking thirteen\"?", "answer": "1984", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a276", "question": "What US city is mentioned in the first line of the Bob Seger song \"Turn the Page\"?", "answer": "Omaha", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4fd", "question": "What do you get when you mix white rum, lime juice, mint and sugar?", "answer": "A Mojito", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389cc", "question": "What animal's head is placed on a stick in \"Lord of the Flies\"?", "answer": "A pig's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600242374be4723ccac22182", "question": "Which leading English poet of was killed in action during World War I one week before the end of the war?", "answer": "Wilfred Owen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac57", "question": "Which ship was Titanic's sister ship?", "answer": "The Olympic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe52bf01bf59ab7d2e38105", "question": "What does \"quid pro quo\" mean in English?", "answer": "Something for something", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b958", "question": "Who was pictured on the first US adhesive stamp?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c90d0ee52800b05cac20f0f", "question": "What is Eisoptrophobia?", "answer": "The fear of mirrors", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5901da79709c1c34536e6eaf", "question": "In ice hockey, how many players for each team are allowed on the ice at the same time?", "answer": "Six", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a98a", "question": "What city named its airport after Leonardo da Vinci?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339db9", "question": "How does the hook-handed Woody Harrelson lose his right hand in the film \"Kingpin\"?", "answer": "In a bowling ball return", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0fd", "question": "Before he escaped and returned to France, Napoleon had been exiled to what island in 1814?", "answer": "Elba", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1de", "question": "Which members of the \"Bee Gees\" were twins?", "answer": "Maurice and Robin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb67", "question": "What is the name of the six-pointed star which is the symbol of Judaism?", "answer": "Star of David", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab0fd0baab681b0929216a", "question": "Valentine's Day is also known as the \"Feast of...\" what?", "answer": "Saint Valentine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae0", "question": "What small carrier attached to a motorcycle shares its name with a brandy cocktail?", "answer": "Sidecar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d8", "question": "By what name is Theodore Kaczynski better known?", "answer": "The Unabomber", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399c1", "question": "What comedy duo\u2019s movies include 1978\u2019s \"Up in Smoke\" and 1981\u2019s \"Nice  Dreams\"?", "answer": "Cheech and Chong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd6b", "question": "In photography, what kind of \"number\" is used to measure lens speed?", "answer": "f", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9e8", "question": "Which is the fourth planet from the Sun?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5902a180cad1ec93f27df777", "question": "What are the main ingredients in a Cafe Cubano?", "answer": "Espresso and demerara sugar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4a98c361d1b4d384d5d691", "question": "What is the name of the ranch the Cartwright family operates in the TV show \"Bonanza\"?", "answer": "Ponderosa Ranch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3d6", "question": "The tune \"Rhapsody in Blue\" was first performed in which year?", "answer": "1924", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef5cd86ce05a3942286e27", "question": "What kick does Daniel use to win the tournament in \"The Karate Kid\"?", "answer": "Crane kick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398aa", "question": "What disability does Dustin Hoffman's character have in the movie \"Rain Man\"?", "answer": "Autism", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad9e", "question": "On March 1, 1872, what became the first National Park in the US?", "answer": "Yellowstone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b32e", "question": "What was the leading cause of death in the late 19th century?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5af25da6b63e5727cf5a4867", "question": "What year did Mariah Carey release the single \"All I Want For Christmas Is You\"?", "answer": "1994", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cdd2877e98cb97778a3b", "question": "Which country is the largest producer of vanilla?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a50", "question": "What 1973 single was Carly Simon\u2019s only single to top the Billboard charts?", "answer": "You're So Vain", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be77", "question": "What does an NFL referee signal by stretching his arms out at his sides with his palms down?", "answer": "Unsportsmanlike Conduct", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b32362bbf195a31e15d73b8", "question": "What year was the character of Betty Crocker first introduced?", "answer": "1921", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a351", "question": "Which is colder, the North or South Pole?", "answer": "The South Pole", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca42", "question": "Which vital organ does the adjective renal refer to?\u00a0", "answer": "Kidney\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecd988ec223966ae8f88e3", "question": "Who was the initial casting choice for the role of the Terminator?", "answer": "O.J. Simpson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b604e662d71a53651001", "question": "Which university features a library named in honor of Dr. Seuss?", "answer": "University of California, San Diego", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecd86fec223966ae8f88dc", "question": "What actor\u2019s face inspired \"Halloween\" baddie Michael Myers\u2019 mask?", "answer": "William Shatner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f5c", "question": "Who painted the world famous \"Mona Lisa\"?", "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7d079877e98cb97778a62", "question": "In which US state can you find the \"Garden of the Gods\"?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ae860a84007905755f79e8f", "question": "What year was Julius Caeser assassinated", "answer": "44 BC", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398cb", "question": "What 1968 movie starred Jack Lemmon and Walter Matthau sharing an apartment?", "answer": "The Odd Couple", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a097", "question": "\"Michelle\" and \"Julia\" are songs by which group?", "answer": "The Beatles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e073fe83fe1f2a824b8c", "question": "What filmmaker was offered \"honorary Aryan\" status by Joseph Goebbels despite his Jewish background?", "answer": "Fritz Lang", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae9b", "question": "Who was the first European explorer to sail into New York Bay?", "answer": "Giovanni da Verrazano", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aff8", "question": "What were the first names of explorers, Lewis and Clark?", "answer": "Meriwether and William", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe526171bf59ab7d2e380f4", "question": "As of 2020, what was the top selling beer in the world?", "answer": "Snow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e37", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"Up the Mountain to Alm-Uncle\"?", "answer": "Heidi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b928", "question": "What color is the smoke announcing the election of a new pope?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339daf", "question": "What is the name of the Japanese anime starring a wandering samurai with a cross shaped scar?", "answer": "Rurouni Kenshin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe93a576bd93ce3a4e5f695", "question": "Which extinction event was caused by human activity?", "answer": "Holocene extinction", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b805", "question": "In the clothing store name \"L. L. Bean\", what do the letters \"L\" stand for?", "answer": "Leon Leonwood", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133992b", "question": "Which one of opera\u2019s \"Three Tenor\u2019s\" names translates in English as \"Quiet Sunday\"?", "answer": "Placido Domingo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecdcfaec223966ae8f88fb", "question": "In the film \"Goodfellas\", what airline is robbed?", "answer": "Lufthansa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff516a8ff04d658268c92f2", "question": "What was America's first major fast food chain?", "answer": "White Castle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a899b7960d398dc9cf7a69d", "question": "In film, who is the alter ego of Daniel Hillard?", "answer": "Mrs. Doubtfire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe52bc11bf59ab7d2e38104", "question": "With what skill did Odysseus defeat Penelope\u2019s suitors?", "answer": "Archery", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390c7", "question": "Who is the subject of Jean Anouilh's play \"L'Alouette\"?", "answer": "Joan of Arc", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395bf", "question": "When the Simpsons go camping, where does Maggie spend her first night?", "answer": "With bears in a cave", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aff", "question": "What was Radar's real first name on the sitcom \"M*A*S*H\"?", "answer": "Walter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc01", "question": "In what year did photography become an integral part of Vogue Magazine?", "answer": "1913", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febaee37e83c707845b20f8", "question": "What year was the first black hole discovered?", "answer": "1971", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339df3", "question": "What movie's theme was remixed in 2005 into Crazy Frog's biggest hit?", "answer": "Beverly Hills Cop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a184", "question": "In the cartoon \"Wacky Races\", who drove the Creepy Coupe?", "answer": "The Gruesome Twosome", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae9340574a5ce6b56b8238", "question": "Who was the Roman equivalent of the Greek goddess Hebe?", "answer": "Juventas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396f0", "question": "What type of pet gets into hot water in \"Fatal Attraction\"?", "answer": "Rabbit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d0c12596a59cbdfbd380", "question": "Who said, \"Slanderers do not hurt me because they do not hit me\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c85a", "question": "What disease grounded astronaut Ken Mattingly from Apollo 13?", "answer": "The measles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59cdb41265ff7d326b622a84", "question": "What year was Budweiser first introduced?", "answer": "1876", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ae85eb74007905755f79e89", "question": "Shiitake, Enoki, Button, Porcini are all types of what?", "answer": "Mushrooms", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b1f201dd7bf43be5e797", "question": "What does it mean to \"86\" something?", "answer": "Get rid of it", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ee3", "question": "What brand of contraceptive did Elaine hoard on the TV show \"Seinfeld\"?", "answer": "The Today sponge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdab94a0b8cce1e6fda7054", "question": "Which person is known for publishing \"The Interpretation of Dreams\"?", "answer": "Sigmund Freud", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c77b", "question": "What reptile's image is the logo of a popular French sportswear company?", "answer": "The crocodile's", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c111877e98cb97778971", "question": "Where is the \"Garden of the Sleeping Giant\"?", "answer": "Fiji", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b373281c3f17ccc40c8e2b", "question": "In \"The Wizard of Oz\", what was the lion in search of?", "answer": "Courage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ddd", "question": "Who reveals \"the man behind the curtain\" in \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "Toto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c54", "question": "Whitney Houston's self-titled debut album was released in what year?", "answer": "1985", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc4bd6ce05a3942286f36", "question": "\"The War of the Worlds\" was first broadcast on radio in what year?", "answer": "1938", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c945", "question": "Kr is the chemical symbol for which element?", "answer": "Krypton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febd5e17e83c707845b2167", "question": "What was Charlie Brown's father's profession?", "answer": "Barber", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb9c67e83c707845b213f", "question": "What do you call someone who studies sea shells?", "answer": "Conchologist", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bb356ef2627b8fe95581be0", "question": "Other than English, what is the main language in Guam?", "answer": "Chamorro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab63", "question": "In what city would you find the infamous Alcatraz?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a698", "question": "Xerox was founded in 1906 In what U.S. City?", "answer": "Rochester, New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133add5", "question": "The Khmer words for \"city temple\" give what building its name?", "answer": "Angkor Wat", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf1d", "question": "In the nursery rhyme what is Friday's child?", "answer": "Loving and Giving", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d8", "question": "From which bridge did Barry Miller fall from in the 1977 movie \"Saturday Night Fever\"?", "answer": "The Verrazano-Narrows Bridge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc144d469bb8041d07a086", "question": "What is mistletoe used for according to Polish folklore?", "answer": "Ward off evil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febaddb7e83c707845b20f4", "question": "Approximately, how much horsepower can one horse produce?", "answer": "15", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c0", "question": "Lake Vanern is the largest lake in which country?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388bb", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"Romeo and Juliet\", what is Juliet's surname?", "answer": "Capulet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4cb", "question": "What day did the Battle of the Somme begin?", "answer": "July 1, 1916", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b24b", "question": "The Bolshevik Revolution is sometimes known by the name of what month in which it began?", "answer": "October", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b61b", "question": "The \"de Havilland Comet IV\" was what?", "answer": "A jet plane", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ba", "question": "What did Freud call the female counterpart of the Oedipus complex?", "answer": "The Elektra complex", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b38a", "question": "What was the capital of East Germany?", "answer": "East Berlin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7d01a877e98cb97778a5b", "question": "Nova Scotia is Latin for what?", "answer": "New Scotland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5d1", "question": "What name is given to a triangular or fanlike river?", "answer": "Delta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c49d", "question": "Self-rising flour contains what crucial ingredient?", "answer": "Baking powder", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a431", "question": "The remains of which ancient city are found in Iraq?", "answer": "Babylon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339845", "question": "Julie Andrews won an Oscar for her role in what Disney classic?", "answer": "Mary Poppins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc5e5ec223966ae8f8884", "question": "Infamous English prisoner, Charles Bronson, was played by what actor in the 2008 film \"Bronson\"?", "answer": "Tom Hardy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a0df20565ad31a57c79c", "question": "Which US President had the first phone installed at the White House?", "answer": "Rutherford Hayes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca11", "question": "What is the fear of lice called?", "answer": "Pediculophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e64", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Inspector Gadget?", "answer": "Don Adams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b19a", "question": "What was the name of the official 1972 Summer Olympics logo?", "answer": "Bright Sun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133908a", "question": "What well known Russian author was also a doctor?", "answer": "Anton Chekhov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8fb8e01dd7bf43be5e853", "question": "Wild Turkey is what kind of alcohol?", "answer": "Straight bourbon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f16690f7c52aae91cc07af", "question": "What is New Year's Eve called in Scotland?", "answer": "Hogmanay", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b36e121c3f17ccc40c8e08", "question": "What common household object appears in the opening scene of the film \"The Sixth Sense\"?", "answer": "A light bulb", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a76b", "question": "What desert gets its name from the Arabic word meaning \"desert\"?", "answer": "Sahara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b845", "question": "What is a perfect score in bowling?", "answer": "300", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cac0", "question": "What is the most abundant metal in Earth's core?", "answer": "Iron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad2e", "question": "Captain James Cook discovered what country in 1769 and claimed it for Great Britain?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397fb", "question": "Who had a 1982 No.1 hit with \"Happy Talk\"?", "answer": "Captain Sensible", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea43dfff048f679a45ab8a", "question": "What condition refers to a low oxygen level in the blood?", "answer": "Hypoxia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338abf", "question": "Margaret Munnerlyn Mitchell, author of the book \"Gone with the Wind\", was born in what city?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c1d", "question": "What were the last two letters added to the english alphabet?", "answer": "J and U", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5de", "question": "Saginaw Bay opens into what body of water?", "answer": "Lake Huron", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b6d", "question": "Who won a Best Supporting Actor Oscar for the 2004 movie \"Million Dollar Baby\"?", "answer": "Morgan Freeman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a004", "question": "What British TV series featured Jeff Tracy and Lady Penelope Creighton-Ward?", "answer": "Thunderbirds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cac9", "question": "What chemical element is symbolized with Sn?", "answer": "Tin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af87", "question": "What did the British army do to the US Capitol building in 1814?", "answer": "Set it on fire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59071d013745b36be73039d3", "question": "Who is credited with inventing the V-2 rocket for Nazi Germany and later the Saturn V rocket for the United States?", "answer": "Wernher von Braun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede1066ce05a3942286dc0", "question": "What city did Frank Sinatra help immortalize as \"That Toddlin' Town\"?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab99", "question": "Which US state shares a nickname with the Australian state of Queensland?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c233", "question": "What fashion designer was responsible for the \"New Look\"?", "answer": "Christian Dior", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d0e12596a59cbdfbd382", "question": "Which country was the first to enact daylight savings time?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c966", "question": "If you are afraid of flying, what phobia do you have?", "answer": "Aviatophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c683", "question": "Which metal, in its purest form, has the highest melting point?", "answer": "Tungsten", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af73", "question": "What dam was built during the 1930s, creating Lake Mead?", "answer": "Hoover Dam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d4042596a59cbdfbd3a0", "question": "What do websites use to remember your preferences?", "answer": "Cookies", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f6ec7a9e54d890926f6ca", "question": "What city is home to the tallest skyscraper in the world?", "answer": "Dubai, UAE -- The Burj Khalifa soars over Dubai at a height of 2,717 ft.  It has 163 floors with a hotel, residences and offices.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c678", "question": "In which US state can one find Kodiak Bears?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394da", "question": "What was Shari Lewis' hand puppet called?", "answer": "Lamb Chop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a553613e1c6f9840ba31a4", "question": "Who won the 1990 Nobel Peace Prize?", "answer": "Mikhail Gorbachev", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a006", "question": "What movie kills off a racehorse named Khartoum?", "answer": "The Godfather", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69b0620565ad31a57c75a", "question": "What was Germany's code name for its planned invasion of the the United Kingdom during World War II?", "answer": "Operation Sea Lion", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7d0", "question": "Which chemical element did the ancients call brimstone?", "answer": "Sulfur", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba6", "question": "What is the capital of Wyoming?", "answer": "Cheyenne", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af21", "question": "What organisation was founded in 1961 by British lawyer Peter Benenson?", "answer": "Amnesty International", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d077c9870e6f05ba600867", "question": "What film starred Drew Barrymore, Mary-Louise Parker, and Matthew McConaughey?", "answer": "Boys on the Side", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b372481c3f17ccc40c8e22", "question": "What English party was politician Arthur Hayday associated with?", "answer": "Labour Party", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff6667552a821ff76ae8af7", "question": "What miracle is Saint Valentine said to have performed shortly before his death?", "answer": "According to legend, Valentine restored the sight of his own jailer's daughter.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339445", "question": "What was the name of Tom Hanks' character in the movie \"Cast Away\"?", "answer": "Chuck Noland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7360deec85e375820b258", "question": "What was the name of the doctor who treated John Wilkes Booth's fractured leg after he shot President Lincoln?", "answer": "Dr. Samuel Mudd", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d80a2596a59cbdfbd3be", "question": "Which ancient wonder was burned down by a fame-seeking arsonist?", "answer": "Artemis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c0c", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Of Mice and Men\"?", "answer": "John Steinbeck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59675ca32b59efe0e9417e95", "question": "The dragonfly has six legs but rarely does what?", "answer": "Walk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4a94db61d1b4d384d5d672", "question": "Who created Popeye?", "answer": "Elzie Segar", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59008d29cf842fa4c4ba96a7", "question": "If you suffer from diplopia, what do you have?", "answer": "Double vision", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b7", "question": "Which Actor played Chachi Arcola on the TV show \"Happy Days\"?", "answer": "Scott Baio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ca3c0e44f0f6af5b06662b", "question": "A \"peck\" is how many imperial quarts?", "answer": "8", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6a1736c0f9723ab15cb39", "question": "The Ishtar Gate was the main entrance to which ancient city?", "answer": "Babylon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6b", "question": "Who played the role of TV's C. J. Barnes?", "answer": "David Spade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ac", "question": "In 1983, who became the first African American to win the Miss America Pageant?", "answer": "Vanessa Williams", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015f62afe83fe1f2a824c1c", "question": "During which period in Japanese history did \"Seven Samurai\" take place?", "answer": "Sengoku", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e14406d333868d34d726", "question": "Which civilization was centered around the city of Tenochtitlan?", "answer": "Aztec", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d0a", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"The Edge of Reason\"?", "answer": "Bridget Jones's Diary", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a898", "question": "What city is home to the Telstra Tower?", "answer": "Canberra", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ede", "question": "What position was first held by Kenesaw Mountain Landis?", "answer": "US Baseball commissioner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dbc", "question": "In what 1863 short story does Philip Nolan renounce his US citizenship?", "answer": "The Man Without a Country", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b53e", "question": "What letter is most used in the English language?", "answer": "E", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b34", "question": "What woodwind instrument is sometimes called a \"licorice stick\"?", "answer": "Clarinet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c506", "question": "What is a group of hyenas called?", "answer": "A cackle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58c9f74cb4e2c7fbd3896747", "question": "In the beer world, what does the abbreviation F.G. stand for?", "answer": "Final gravity", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fc856c1abc30a8194e188b3", "question": "Who was piloting the Enola Gay when it dropped the atomic bomb on Hiroshima?", "answer": "The bombardier, Tom Ferebee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e9", "question": "The first American blood bank was established in 1937 in which city?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febba977e83c707845b2145", "question": "What was the first Super Bowl to use Roman numerals in its title?", "answer": "Super Bowl V", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394d7", "question": "What made-for-TV movie starred Alfre Woodard as Eunice Evers?", "answer": "Miss Evers' Boys", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec0", "question": "Which German prison camp did Pat Reid try to escape from?", "answer": "Colditz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b293", "question": "What European country ruled Macau until December 20, 1999?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339116", "question": "Who wrote the 1896 science fiction novel \"The Island of Doctor Moreau\"?", "answer": "H. G. Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe909eb01dd7bf43be5e893", "question": "What is trepanning?", "answer": "The drilling of holes in the head and scraping or cutting of the skull", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a9e95017ccba3ffe45786db", "question": "Which computer scientist was largely responsible for the design of \"FLOW-MATIC\", the first English-like data processing language?", "answer": "Grace Hopper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c489", "question": "What is the term for the visible surface of the Sun?", "answer": "Photosphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b14b", "question": "What typewriter key was introduced by Remington in 1878, ending the need for two keys for each letter?", "answer": "Shift key", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339edf", "question": "What position was first held by Trygve Lie?", "answer": "UN Secretary General", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339973", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what IQ does Comic Book Guy posses?", "answer": "170", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3d6", "question": "What is the only US state with a single syllable name?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b493", "question": "What year were the first modern-day Olympic Games held?", "answer": "1896", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd81f97d0de9af39e9d4697", "question": "What was the first global empire in history?", "answer": "Portuguese Empire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b03", "question": "Which character killed Elizabeth Vladimir Lensky?", "answer": "Eugene Onegin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bf9", "question": "Who won a Pulitzer Prize for her novel \"So Big\"?", "answer": "Edna Ferber", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eec", "question": "Actor Jim Caviezel was struck by lightning during the filming of what movie?", "answer": "The Passion of the Christ", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c63d", "question": "A Calorie is a measurement of what?", "answer": "Energy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ed0", "question": "Before he turned to acting, what was Marky Mark's only number one song?", "answer": "Good Vibrations", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb11", "question": "What early arcade game used a trackball rather than a joystick?", "answer": "Missile Command", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937ede908d98002fdd633cd", "question": "In which city is the C.N. Tower?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ae9270574a5ce6b56b822d", "question": "What instrument in an automobile measures distance travelled?", "answer": "Odometer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cabb", "question": "Which part of the body suffers from Microphthalmia?", "answer": "The eyes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ac", "question": "Which country were the 1952 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f72e9a9e54d890926f6ee", "question": "What is the only country that displays the Bible on its national flag?", "answer": "The Dominican Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e3", "question": "Which band recorded the live album titled \"Strangers in the Night\"?", "answer": "UFO", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f16506df9b80650dbe7f93b", "question": "Where is ESPN's headquarters located?", "answer": "Bristol, Connecticut", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a899bed60d398dc9cf7a6a2", "question": "In the body, what is the CNS?", "answer": "Central Nervous System", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d65", "question": "What year did J. R. R. Tolkien publish \"The Hobbit\"?", "answer": "1937", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cc4", "question": "Who painted the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel?", "answer": "Michelangelo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fb5", "question": "In his Snake Plissken movies, what kind of snake is Kurt Russell's stomach tattoo?", "answer": "Cobra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bac0", "question": "While in play, how many players are on a water polo team?", "answer": "7", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f7547a9e54d890926f708", "question": "In what month does Russia celebrate the October Revolution?", "answer": "November", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd66a37a5bfecdd737e0881", "question": "What were most pennies made out of in 1943?", "answer": "Steel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffcfb3d9dc5ec6cd98a8315", "question": "Who painted the Mona Lisa?", "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac0a", "question": "What is the name of Canada's national anthem?", "answer": "O Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5c9", "question": "The Santa Clara Valley is located in which US state?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4b58a06d333868d34d6e9", "question": "In the U.S., what famous slogan first appeared on World War I recruiting posters?", "answer": "\"I want you\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fa2", "question": "A story of ones own life is referred to as what?", "answer": "Autobiography", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c181", "question": "The skin of which animal is used to make the finest grade Morocco Leather?", "answer": "Goat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b79c", "question": "What color is the central square on a Scrabble board?", "answer": "Pink", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8cc0694b094db9158309c", "question": "What was the category for \u201cBest Picture\u201d named during the 1st Academy Awards in 1929?", "answer": "Outstanding Picture", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c244", "question": "How many sides does a hexagon have?", "answer": "Six", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398f7", "question": "Who played Roseanne\u2019s sister, Jackie, on the TV show \u201cRoseanne\u201d?", "answer": "Laurie Metcalf", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e13", "question": "What 1980 film is named for the legendary square-shaped capital of Kublai Khan?", "answer": "Xanadu", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab51", "question": "Ljubljana is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Slovenia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b7ab8e46490a8cc1a6e528e", "question": "In \"The Adventures of Pinocchio\", who did Pinocchio accidentally kill?", "answer": "The Talking Cricket", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394ee", "question": "What actress fell for an American reporter in the 1953 movie \"Roman Holiday\"?", "answer": "Audrey Hepburn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60023f1e4be4723ccac22162", "question": "What is tallest dog breed in the world?", "answer": "Irish Wolfhound", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133934e", "question": "Who played Alex's sister, Mallory, on the TV show \"Family Ties\"?", "answer": "Justine Bateman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc2f265cee580c7f8fd1e52", "question": "Who said, \"Winners never quit, and quitters never win.\"?", "answer": "Vince Lombardi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e4d", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"Steel\"?", "answer": "Shaquille O'Neal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c370", "question": "What layer of the Earth's atmosphere sits between the troposphere and mesosphere?", "answer": "Stratosphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e02", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek goddess Eris?", "answer": "Discordia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad4a", "question": "Gangster Al Capone was eventually arrested and convicted on what charge?", "answer": "Tax evasion", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b2cc01dd7bf43be5e7a3", "question": "What did Mae Jemison, the first African-American woman to go to space, study while in medical school?", "answer": "Modern dance", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a95", "question": "In ancient Greece, what river did the souls of dead people have to cross?", "answer": "Styx", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0bf", "question": "What famous chemist died in 1934 from a blood disease contracted by the effects of radiation exposure?", "answer": "Marie Curie", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339026", "question": "Who famously said \"When in doubt tell the truth.\"?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a071", "question": "Who filled in for Ringo Starr on the Beatles' 1964 world tour?", "answer": "Jimmie Nicol", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c00", "question": "What year was actor Jack Nicholson born?", "answer": "1937", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a045", "question": "Keyrock, the simple minded cave-man lawyer was played by what comedian on Saturday Night Live?", "answer": "Phil Hartman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd85ee347d002c297e4c7", "question": "Who flew too close to the Sun??", "answer": "Icarus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c758", "question": "What vitamin, found in carrots, helps maintain the acuity of your vision?", "answer": "Vitamin A", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d4702ff8e329de4f87788f", "question": "In electronics, what does the word modem stand for?", "answer": "Modulator-demodulator", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4a8649076251badbeab8", "question": "What Greek mathematician is considered the founder and father of Geometry?", "answer": "Euclid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abcd", "question": "On which river does the city of Dublin stand?", "answer": "Liffey\u00a0River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b1e", "question": "Who wrote the book \"The Wonderful Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "L. Frank Baum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c339", "question": "What is the acronym for Thomas A. Swift's Electric Rifle?", "answer": "Taser", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b40c", "question": "What was Banlgadesh formerly known as until its independence?", "answer": "East Pakistan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab1997baab681b09292192", "question": "What year was NASCAR founded?", "answer": "1948", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dad", "question": "What is the only bird in the famous witches' cauldron ingredient list from Macbeth?", "answer": "An owl", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396a9", "question": "Which two friends won Oscars for their screenplay of the 1997 movie \"Good Will Hunting\"?", "answer": "Ben Affleck and Matt Damon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b92a", "question": "What nationality was Dr. James Naismith, the inventor of basketball?", "answer": "Canadian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bffd", "question": "Which famous artist designed the Chupa Chups logo in 1969?", "answer": "Salvador Dali", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390dd", "question": "In the Winnie-the-Pooh stories what is Kanga\u2019s baby called?", "answer": "Roo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0af", "question": "Who was Al Gore's running mate in the 2000 presidential election?", "answer": "Joe Lieberman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa75", "question": "Which European city is famous for its Latin Quarter?", "answer": "Paris\u00a0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4a5b49076251badbeab4", "question": "Six Flags, the famous Texas amusement park, was named after what?", "answer": "The six governments that have ruled Texas -- Specifically, France, Spain, Mexico, the Confederacy, Texas and the U.S.", "category": "history"}]